Keval Dholakiya

Surat, Gujarat, India



kevald47@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/keval-d



+91 70968 23708



https://github.com/KDholakiya

Summary

Hi! I am Keval Dholakiya, a Full Stack Developer with experience in various technologies and frameworks. I have worked with companies like Zippia, Upwork, Walk With Web, and Harvices. I have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Applications from Saurashtra University and certifications in hackathons, final-year projects, and academics. I also have skills in problem-solving, effective communication, penetration testing, web application security, and software development. In my free time, I enjoy comedy, gardening, yoga, travelling, and browsing Reddit.

Experience



Software Engineer

Zippia

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

- Skilled Full Stack Engineer with expertise in creating and improving components and services.
- Proficient in optimizing old code and enhancing performance to increase productivity.
- Demonstrated proficiency in scripting with Bash/Shell and developing JavaScript utilities for streamlined workflows.
- Proven track record in optimizing web page performance by leveraging Lighthouse scores, resulting in enhanced user experiences and improved loading times.
- Experienced in collaborating with cross-functional teams to deliver successful projects

p Experienced Top Rated Plus Freelancer

Upwork

Jun 2018 - Present (5 years 7 months)

I'm an experienced Full Stack Engineer with comprehensive skills in Java/Spring Boot, JavaScript/ TypeScript, Php/Laravel, Python, React Hooks, Communication, Git, Redux.is, Design Patterns, Desktop Application Development, Mobile Application Development, Full-Stack Development, DevOps, AWS, and GCP.

Here are a few highlights of my capabilities:

- Successfully executed diverse projects for various clients, utilizing React, Laravel, Electron.js, Next.js, Figma, WordPress, Firebase, and Express.js, among others.
- Adaptability and expertise enable me to work with diverse technologies and frameworks to deliver tailored and impactful solutions that meet each client's unique requirements.

Please note that my portfolio is available for review on upwork.com/freelancers/~01dad5cbd49807119b.

Notably, my clients/employers have provided favorable reviews, including the following:

- "Keval is a talented developer. He paid attention to all my requirements, asked intelligent questions and was very personable. He completed the task and delivered on time. I certainly recommend him to other clients"
- "Keval has in-depth knowledge of devops and helped me set up my server deployment exactly how I wanted it! Was very helpful with all requests. Id highly recommend him for all your server setup needs."
- "He wrote a neat code and was able to work independently to resolve problems and do his own research. He was readily available and pleasant to communicate with"
- "Keval has been overly accommodating for my needs with migrating our website over to AWS, while being always available even after the project was completed for any related concerns."
- "Keval has done phenomenal work on the e-commerce website with complex flows and calculations"

Full Stack Engineer

Walk With Web

May 2021 - Jan 2022 (9 months)

- We specialize in developing and sustaining digital research for social sciences and humanities.
- I created an e-commerce website for a tea start-up.
- My skills include effective communication, system design, CSS, HTML, Laravel, MySQL, and Javascript.

🚇 Java Developer | React Developer

Harvices

May 2020 - May 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Proficient in Spring boot, Spring Security, React, CSS, HTML, Javascript, MySQL, MongoDB, and Python.
- Played a pivotal role in the making of POS software for Australian clients.
- Designed REST APIs and integrated various web apps.
- Implemented payment gateway integration and incorporated Google Maps for tracking purposes.
- Wrote REST API for an Android app with 100k+ downloads.
- Developed Webhook APIs to integrate with third parties.
- Created an automation tool in Python for generating CRUD for basic entities in Java Spring Boot.

💹 Laravel Developer | React Developer

Harvices

Sep 2019 - May 2020 (9 months)

- Full-stack developer with experience in creating REST APIs in Laravel and Spring Boot.
- Proficient in developing software applications that facilitate efficient record and report management.
- Experienced in server management, including the creation and management of custom mail servers, as well as application deployment on servers.
- Skilled in executing the CI/CD flow using Jenkins.
- Contributed to the development of several applications that have been adopted by a vast number of users.
- Strong technical expertise coupled with experience in the field has enabled me to make significant contributions to my previous employer.

Education



Saurashtra University

BCA, Computer Science

2017 - 2020

Skills

React.js • Next.js • JavaScript • Spring Boot • Java • PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Redux.js • Git

Honors & Awards

Top Rated Plus Freelancer Badge - Upwork

Jul 2022

"Top Rated Plus" recognizes freelancers who consistently deliver premium quality work on high-budget or longer-term projects. This showcases my dedication and sets me apart from others.

up 100% Job Success Score at Upwork - Upwork

Jan 2022

The Job Success Score (JSS) is a metric that measures the satisfaction of my clients with my work history on Upwork's platform. It takes into account my clients' satisfaction as evidenced by relationships, feedback, and job outcomes over time. A high JSS score can help me stand out in the Upwork marketplace, which in turn means I can spend less time looking for clients and more time working with them.